## **Ihor Vasyliev**

## Bulgaria, ihor.software@gmail.com

LINKS	https://ihor-software.github.io/website
PROFILE	I am a software developer specializing in making websites and mobile apps. I have 3+ years of experience in software development. I like facing challenges and handling tough situations. I'm all about being responsible and keeping things running smoothly. I also appreciate open communication.
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY	
Jul 2023 — Jan 2024	Full Stack Developer, Radency
	Health system for hospitals, patients and doctors. Technologies: NodeJS, Express/NestJS, REST, Swagger, TypeScript, React, Redux, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, Chromatic, RabbitMQ, JWT, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Redis, Docker. Developed from scratch.
	I have been working on: system architecture design, authorization logic, custom UI components, real time chat, AI assistant, documents scanner, code review.
Dec 2021 — Jul 2023	iOS Developer, Blackberry
	Mobile application support. Technologies: Objective C, Swift.
	I have been working on: authorization logic, test coverage, bug fixing, devices debugging, code review, obj-c to swift migration.
Jun 2021 — Dec 2021	iOS Developer, Epam
	Food ordering application. Provides login features, loads products to menu, adds products to cart. It has functionality to setup profile information such as address, phone number, credit cards. Eventually, it lets user to order food via application to the desired place.
	I have worked on: architecture design, UI elements, authorization confirmation, API calls, code optimization, lint setup, adding food to bucket functionality, proceeding with bucket, menu page, code review.
Feb 2021 — Jun 2021	iOS Developer, Epam
	Internal iOS projects.
	I have worked on: SwiftUI lists, API based applications (Weather, Notes, Cinema, Crypto converter, News, advanced Weather), notification center, advanced notes with folder structure and persistent CoreData storage upgraded with quick fetch mechanism, photo structuring and editing functionality, animations and mobile games, touch recognition and drawing functionality with lines smothering, UI elements class adaptation suitable for wide range screen resolutions, advanced lists search and filtering functionality, code review.
EDUCATION	
Sep 2018 — Jun 2022	Bachelor of Computer Science, Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics
	I studied:
	JS development & algorithmical thinking, discrete math, software development practises, .Net developing, .Net Core developing, Windows forms, advanced algorithms, architecture patterns, database managment, building advanced sql queries, networking protocols, debugging and prototyping network, websites development, websites hosting, javascript frameworks(React, Angular), iOT, Mobile development(iOS, Android), High standard industry projects(including several user roles, complex database design, innovative algorithm development, and linking multiple platforms to work in one system as one whole, such as iOT smart device, mobile application, and Desktop/Website application. All of those has access to internet and can be sold as a system for a tech company or to a chain of stores in my case).
Sep 2022 — Jun 2024	Master of Computer Science, Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics
	I studied:
	tests coverage, tests automation, computer vision, advanced math, system optimization, graphs, scientific researches, business management, probability theory, philosophy, function optimization, developing algorithms, big data, neural networks, embedding AI functions in software.

SKILLS Objective-C SQL

Swift	Docker
Firebase	TypeScript
Node.js	React

LANGUAGES

English